Guide to the Papers of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut (1910-2003) 1738-2006 AR 25309 / MF 932
Center for Jewish History, Publisher.
Elizabeth Strauss Plaut Collection
1738-2006
bulk 1973-1999
Plaut, Elizabeth S., 1910-2003
This collection contains the genealogical research of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut. Papers to be found here include extensive correspondence, family trees, and research notes on the genealogy of the Plaut and Strauss families.
14 linear feet + 1 oversized box
AR 25309
Leo Baeck Institute
Biographical Note
Elizabeth Strauss was born on October 12, 1910 in New York City, the second child of Harry Strauss and Therese Abraham Strauss. A few years after the birth of his daughter Harry Strauss died of typhoid fever, and Therese Strauss relocated with her children to her family home in Cincinnati, where the family resided with her parents, Victor and Emma Abraham.
Elizabeth Strauss attended the University of Cincinnati, where she majored in zoology. While continuing to study for her teacher's certificate, she met W. Gunther Plaut, a recent immigrant from Germany who was studying at the Hebrew Union College. They were married on November 10, 1938.
The following September the couple moved when Gunther Plaut became assistant rabbi of the Washington Boulevard Temple in Chicago. There Elizabeth Plaut started a Judaica shop in addition to her duties as rebbetzin. In 1942 the couple had a son. The family moved several times due to Gunther Plaut's various assignments as a chaplain in the U.S. Army during World War II. After a return to Chicago, where the family expanded to include a daughter, they moved to St. Paul, Minnesota, when Gunther Plaut became rabbi at the Mount Zion Hebrew Congregation. The family remained there for thirteen years. During this time Elizabeth Plaut was also very active as the rabbi's wife. In addition, in 1952 she created "Holiplay," a children's game about the Jewish holidays. Finally, the family made its last relocation when Gunther Plaut became rabbi for the Holy Blossom Temple in Toronto, Ontario, a much larger congregation than that in St. Paul.
It was during the early 1970s that Elizabeth Plaut became involved in documenting the genealogy of the Strauss, Plaut, and related families. Over the following three decades she accumulated numerous family trees and voluminous research on the family history, collecting information from family members as well as print sources and archival records. This work culminated in the publication of articles in genealogical periodicals such as Search and Toledot, as well as in three books.
Elizabeth Strauss Plaut died on September 13, 2003 (16 Ellul 5763).
Published Books:
1996 Guggenheim/ Wormser Family: a Genealogical 300-Year Memoir
2000 Gumprichs of Münster/ Westphalia: a Tale of Four Continents
2007 Plaut Family: Tracing the Legacy (with Jonathan V. Plaut as editor and an introduction and additional research by Karen S. Franklin)
Scope and Content Note
The Elizabeth Strauss Plaut collection holds the genealogical research that culminated in the production of three books,Gumprichs of Münster/ Westphalia: a Tale of Four Continents,Guggenheim/ Wormser Family: a Genealogical 300-Year Memoir, and Plaut Family: Tracing the Legacy.
Nearly all of the series in this collection consist of extensive genealogical correspondence, family trees, and research notes, with most folders holding family trees or notes on family trees.Series I holds research on the Plaut family, with much of it divided by the location in Germany from which the family derived. In addition, this series also includes material on the Gumprich and Rosenthal families, related to the genealogy of Selma Gumprich Plaut. Genealogy on the Strauss family will be found in Series II, and consists of research into many branches of the family tree; the most prominent branches of the family loosely form the basis for subseries within Series II, including the Abraham, Strauss,Guggenheim/ Wormser,Wertheimer,Wisebart,Kline,Rauh, Mack, and Dreyfoos families. General genealogical research, or research whose branch was not clearly identified by Elizabeth Strauss comprises Series III: General and Unsorted Genealogical Files. Oversized family trees of both Plaut and Strauss ancestors are included in Series IV. Papers pertaining to the writing or publishing of Elizabeth Strauss' books make up Series V, and include drafts of her books on the Gumprich and Guggenheim/ Wormser families as well as some correspondence with publishers.
Photographs and copies of photographs of family members are often included with the correspondence or collected material on family branches. However, some of these types of material were not included among the genealogical files, and these primarily form Series VI. In addition to photographs, this series holds a few other papers of visual material.
Files unrelated to genealogical research form Series VII. Included here is one folder of personal correspondence, drafts of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut's creative writing and texts for lectures and other public addresses.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in six series:
Series I: W. Gunther Plaut Genealogy, 1738-2006
Subseries 1: Locations, 1738-2005
A) Falkenberg and Felsenberg (Dannenberg Family)
B) Frankershausen
C) Frielendorf
D) Geisa
E) Gudensberg and Obervorschuetz
F) Ottrau
G) Rauschenberg
H) Reichensachsen
I) Rotenburg an der Fulda
J) Schenklengsfeld
K) Schmalkalden
L) Wehrda
M) Willingshausen
N) Other Locations
Subseries 2: Other Research Material, 1860-2006
Subseries 3: Gumprich and Rosenthal Families, 1858-1999
A) Gumprich
B) Rosenthal
Series II: Elizabeth Strauss Plaut Genealogy, 1847-1999
Subseries 1: Abraham/ Strauss, 1851-1999
Subseries 2: Dreifus/ Dreyfus/ Dreyfoos, 1847-1997
Subseries 3: Kline, 1978-1994
Subseries 4: Rauh/ Mack, 1956-1993
Subseries 5: Wertheimer, 1860-1865, 1975-1993
Subseries 6: Wisebart, 1873-1995
Subseries 7: Wormser/ Guggenheim, 1850-1996
Series III: General and Unsorted Genealogical Files, 1950-1999
Series IV: Oversized Family Trees, undated
Series V: Writing and Publishing, 1977-1998
Series VI: Visual Material, 1865-1999
Series VII: Non-Genealogical Material, 1940s-2001
Subseries 1: Writings, Correspondence, and Notes, 1940s-2001
Subseries 2: Collected Material, 1969-1998
Related Material
The LBI Archives also hold a related collection, the Elizabeth Plaut Collection (AR 10087).
The LBI Library has two of Elizabeth Strauss Plaut's books:
The Gumprichs of Muenster/Westphalia: a Tale of Four Continents (st 427)
The Guggenheim/Wormser family: a Genealogical 300-Year Memoir (CS 629 G84 P53 1996)
Separated Material
Some photographs have been removed to the LBI Photograph Collection.
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers.
Access Information
Readers may access the collection by visiting the Lillian Goldman Reading Room at the Center for Jewish History. We recommend reserving the collection in advance; please visit the LBI Online Catalog and click on the "Request" button.
Microfilm
The collection is on thirty-four reels of microfilm (MF 932):
Reel 1: 1/1 - 1/14
Reel 2: 1/15 - 1/39
Reel 3: 1/40 - 1/60
Reel 4: 2/1 - 2/33
Reel 5: 2/34 - 2/59
Reel 6: 2/60 - 3/9
Reel 7: 3/10 - 3/22
Reel 8: 3/23 - 3/46
Reel 9: 3/47 - 4/7
Reel 10: 4/8 - 4/36
Reel 11: 4/37 - 4/56
Reel 12: 4/57 - 5/24
Reel 13: 5/25 - 5/45
Reel 14: 5/46 - 6/14
Reel 15: 6/15 - 6/53
Reel 16: 6/54 - 7/9
Reel 17: 7/10 - 7/43
Reel 18: 7/44 - 7/83
Reel 19: 7/84 - 8/13
Reel 20: 8/14 - 8/43
Reel 21: 8/44 - 9/17
Reel 22: 9/18 - 9/52
Reel 23: 9/53 - 10/5
Reel 24: 10/6 - 10/29
Reel 25: 10/30 - 10/65
Reel 26: 10/66 - 11/20
Reel 27: 11/21 - 11/58
Reel 28: 11/59 - 12/6
Reel 29: 12/7 - 12/32
Reel 30: 12/33 - 12/59
Reel 31: 13/1 - 13/17
Reel 32: 13/18 - 13/25
Reel 33: 13/26 - 14/1
Reel 34: 14/2 - 14/15 and Oversized Material
Abraham family; Dreyfus family; Gumprich family; Plaut, Elizabeth S., 1910-2003; Plaut, W. Gunther, 1912-; Plaut family; Rosenthal family; Strauss family; Wormser family; Genealogists; Jewish families; Jews -- Genealogy; Cincinnati (Ohio); Hesse (Germany); Toronto (Ont.); Correspondence; Genealogical tables; Manuscripts (document genre); Notes
Container List
- Series I: W. Gunther Plaut Genealogy, 1738-2005; 7.875 linear feet.
  Divided into three subseries:
  Subseries 1: Locations
  Subseries 2: Other Research Material
  Subseries 3: Gumprich and Rosenthal Families
  Series I consists of papers created during Elizabeth Strauss Plaut's genealogical research on the Plaut family. It primarily includes research on the Plaut (Blaut/ Blout/ Plauth) family and the related Gumprich and Rosenthal families. This is the largest area of the collection, constituting more than half of it. Much of the arrangement was derived from observation of Elizabeth Plaut's own original arrangement. This original order consisted of five linear feet of material organized by locations of towns in Germany, and one foot of material on the Gumprich and Rosenthal families, as well as approximately two additional feet of research material on the Plaut family with less organization.
  Much of the papers that comprise this series are of a similar nature. Included is correspondence with numerous relatives and research institutions on the family genealogy. The correspondence with relatives very often also mentions family news and events and sometimes includes photographs of family members. Other papers found here include extensive family trees, copies of historical records or extracts from published sources concerning family members, as well a large number of notes on the family genealogy.
  - Subseries 1: Locations, 1738-2005; 5.625 linear feet.
    Subseries 1 is separated by location, as follows:
    A) Falkenberg and Felsenberg (Dannenberg Family)
    B) Frankershausen
    C) Frielendorf
    D) Geisa
    E) Gudensberg and Obervorschuetz
    F) Ottrau
    G) Rauschenberg
    H) Reichensachsen
    I) Rotenburg an der Fulda
    J) Schenklengsfeld
    K) Schmalkalden
    L) Wehrda
    M) Willingshausen
    N) Other Locations
    Subseries 1 is comprised of genealogical research files on the Plaut family arranged by location, following the observed original order. The locations appear to represent the areas in Germany (primarily towns in Hesse and Thuringia) from which the various branches of the family stemmed. Although the location sections have been arranged alphabetically by the name of the area for ease of use, all files originally placed together and marked as belonging to a specific location have not been separated from other files within that location. Some locations with fewer files were originally found in generally alphabetic order; these comprise the section "Other Locations." Within each location, folders predominantly comprised of similar formats, such as correspondence, notes, or family trees, have been grouped together during processing for ease of use, although users should note that most folders within this subseries include family trees or notes on family trees. Folder titles follow the original title of folders provided by Elizabeth Strauss Plaut. Any information provided within a file by Elizabeth Strauss Plaut as to the content of the file has been retained in this finding aid; folders with extensive correspondence include lists of correspondents in the finding aid. Folders originally entitled with an individual's name that hold research about a specific family member's branch of the family tree include the phrase "branch" in the folder title in order to differentiate such papers from files on specific individuals.
    Papers in this subseries primarily include extensive family trees and correspondence, although research notes and photocopies of historical or archival records or clippings pertaining to family members are also located here.
    Elizabeth Strauss Plaut maintained correspondence spanning more than three decades with numerous individuals while pursuing research on the Plaut family. Family members were largely located in the United States and Israel, but also include family in Europe, Canada, South Africa, Japan, and South America. While the correspondence clearly focuses on genealogical research, it also mentions family news and events and other personal topics. A few photographs or photocopies of photographs may be found among the research material. In addition, several memoirs are also located within this subseries; those of Clara Plaut and Bertel Borowsky describe their experiences during World War II and the Holocaust years, while the memoir of Marjorie Hess discusses the family history and significant family events. In addition to family correspondence, some letters within this subseries are with archives or historical societies and include Elizabeth Strauss Plaut's requests for information or photocopies of records from these institutions.
    - A) Falkenberg and Felsenberg (Dannenberg Family)
      - Dannenberg Family - Documentation, 1786-1937, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Dannenberg Family - Family Trees and Charts, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Dannenberg Family - Felsberg Birth Register, 1824-1852 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Dannenberg Family - Research and Correspondence, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Dannenberg, James - Beit Theresienstadt Records, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Dannenberg, James - Correspondence, 1993-1998 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Dannenberg, James - Correspondence, 1994-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - B) Frankershausen
      - Barten and Koenigswarter Families, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1972-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
        Fink, Ester ("Estie") Plaut 1991-1993
        Plaut, Hans and Chava 1972-1985
      - Correspondence, 1973-1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
        Cerf, Edith 1973-1985
        Gruen, Henry 1984-1985
        Katz, Berthold 1973
        Plat-Glik, [Mrs.] 1973-1974
        Plaut, Amos and Ilana 1973-1984
        Plaut, Jacob 1973
        Rubenstein, Flora 1973-1987
      - Correspondence, 1974-1987 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        Bloch, Anne 1976-1980
        Bloch, Julius and Gertie 1974
        Plaut, Jeffrey and Mary 1982
        Plaut, Marianne (Maja) 1985-1987
        Plaut, Mary Onstad 1982-1987
        Plaut, Warner P.B. 1982
      - Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
        Goldsmith, Karl 1976-1985
        Klein, Renate ("Renie") 1984-1987
        Plaut, Andrew 1988
        Plaut, Otto 1975-1978
        Plaut, Rita and Marshall 1977-1986
      - Correspondence - Beckler and Moyse Families, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
        Beckler, Harriet
        Moyse, Jack
      - Correspondence - Bender, Edgar J., 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence - de Plaut, Berta Joshua, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence - Englander, Hilde, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence - Jaffee, Selma (England), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence - Katz, Gad, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence - Lanir, Yael, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Dvorah and Mordecai, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Erich, 1995-1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Esther ("Estie"), 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Gertie, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Guy and Gilles (France), 1982-1996 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Max, 1974-1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Richard - Lipmann Plaut Branch, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence - Strauss, Ilse, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence and Research Material, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
        Adelman, Susan 1991
        Plaut, Zita 1980
      - Correspondence and Research Material - Plaut, Menko - Branch, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 29)
        Plaut, Nelly 1973
        Plaut, Leon undated
      - Family Trees - Blauth/ Plaut, undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Family Trees - Correspondence - Ettinger, Joel, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Family Trees - Correspondence - Weinreb, Daniel, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - Family Trees - Correspondence and Research Material - Plaut, Michael and Jeanette Mendel, 1930, 1973-1987 (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - Family Trees - Drafts, 1974-1988, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - Family Trees - Early Data, 1972-1973, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - Family Trees - Eschwege - Levi/ Abraham, 1982, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Family Trees - [Blaut?], Itzig Abraham (b. 1705), 1990s?- 2005 (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Family Trees - Blaut, Itzik (b. 1600s) Branch, 1974-1980s? (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Abraham Menke Levi - Descendants, 1978-2001, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Abraham Menke Levi - Descendants - Correspondence, 1989-1940 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Jacob, undated (Box OS 128)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Menke (Menko) Leib - Descendants, 1978-1979, 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - Family Trees - Working Charts, 1973-1976, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - Family Trees with Research Material, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - Family Trees with Research Material - Moritz Plaut, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - Loose Material - Family Trees and Research, undated, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - Jacob Leib Plaut Branch, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - Records - Notes and Correspondence, undated, 1959, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Records - Notes and Correspondence - Gad Katz, 1977-1987 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - C) Frielendorf
      - Correspondence, 1973-1987 (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Correspondence, 1974-1993 (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - Correspondence - Alexander, Sue, 1973-1987 (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - Correspondence - Donner/ Gozonsky Family, 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - Correspondence - Goldschmidt Family, 1973-1988 (Box 1, Folder 55)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Harry J.D. - Branch, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Hedwig (Oberaula), 1984 (Box 1, Folder 57)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Juan, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Siegfried Heinemann, 1977-1986 (Box 1, Folder 59)
      - Correspondence and Family Trees - Zeron, Ruth, 1993, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 60)
      - Correspondence and Records, 1973-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence and Research - Plaut Family, 1976-1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Family Trees - Charts with Sources, 1978-1980, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Family Trees - Plaut/ Blout Data, 1916, 1973-1982 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Family Trees - Plaut/ Blout Data - Correspondence, 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Kallman, 1989-1994, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Leiser (Eliezer), 1980s?, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - D) Geisa
      - Blaut, Stephen - Branch Research, 1933, 1973-1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1988-1998 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Correspondence - Blaut, Ernst and Lotte, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Correspondence - Blaut, Mr. [Unidentifed], 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Correspondence - Frazen, Penny, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Correspondence - German Democratic Republic, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - Correspondence - Goldsmith, John H., 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence - Greenbaum, Selma, 1976-1986 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Correspondence - Henry, Carl, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Correspondence - Kaufherr, Mark, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Correspondence - Mack Family, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Correspondence - Meter, [Elizabeth?], 1977 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - Correspondence - Moeller, Gustav and Dieter, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Correspondence - Plant, Richard, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Arthur, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Max, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Max N., 1977 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Thomas, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Correspondence - Schragenheim, Ernst and Ruth, 1979-1988 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Correspondence and Family Trees - Mackenzell Family, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Correspondence and Family Trees - Michael Plaut Branch, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - Correspondence and Notes - Mendelsohn, Joe, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Family Trees, 1972-1989 (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - Family Trees - Blaut, Ernst (Australia), 1982 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Family Trees - Blaut, Meyer Jacob Branch, undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Family Trees - Burghaun, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Family Trees - Mack/ Feinkopf/ Plaut, undated, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Heinemann and Sara Koenig, undated (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Jacob and Minna Plaut, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - Family Trees - Michael (Yehiel) Jacob Plaut Branch, undated, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - Family Trees - Plaut, Rudolf, undated (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Family Trees - Typed, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - Goldschmidt/ Blaut Data, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Notes - Archival and Library Records, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Notes - General and Sources Used, undated, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Notes - Loose, undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - Notes and Bibliographies, undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Plaut, Evelyn - Article - Descendants of Nathan, Jacob, and Minna Plaut, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Plaut, Minna and Jacob, 1976-1986 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Plaut, Rudolf - Descendants, 1973-1977 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Plaut, Sophie Strauss, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - E) Gudensberg and Obervorschuetz
      - a) Gudensberg
        - Gudensberg - Correspondence - Plaut, Stephen and Lottie, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 51)
        - Gudensberg - Correspondence - Plaut, Stephen and Lottie, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 52)
        - Gudensberg - Correspondence - Samuel Family Members, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 53)
        - Gudensberg - Family Trees - Sources, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 54)
      - b) Gudensberg and Obervorschuetz
        - Gudensberg and Obervorschuetz - Correspondence, 1988-1992 (Box 2, Folder 55)
        - Gudensberg and Obervorschuetz - Correspondence - Stephen and Lottie Plaut, 1987-1992 (Box 2, Folder 56)
        - Gudensberg and Obervorschuetz - Family Trees, 1973-1998, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 57)
        - Gudensberg and Obervorschuetz - Records - Notes and Correspondence, 1974-1987 (Box 2, Folder 58)
      - c) Obervorschuetz
        - Obervorschuetz - Correspondence - Tourgeman family, 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 59)
        - Obervorschuetz - Correspondence and Notes, 1979-1997 (Box 2, Folder 60)
        - Obervorschuetz - Family Trees, undated (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - F) Ottrau
      - Correspondence, 1975-1988 (Box 2, Folder 62)
        Pollitz, Molly 1975-1979
        Fitzmaurice, Marcia 1979-1988
      - Correspondence, 1976-1983 (Box 2, Folder 63)
        Bloch, Martha 1976-1983
        Felsenthal, Ruth Spangenthal 1980
        Wallach, Karl Heinz 1976-1979
      - Correspondence, 1984-1993 (Box 2, Folder 64)
        Mallory, Elizabeth ("Liz") 1984-1987
        Lefkowitz, Rosalie 1989-1993
      - Correspondence - Plaut, Feist (Frederick) - Descendants, 1977-1984 (Box 2, Folder 65)
        Bureau of Vital Statistics, New York 1978-1984
        Charno, Florence 1978-1984
        Cypress Hill Cemetery 1977
        Dreifus, Stanley 1977
        Hirschberg, Gunter 1977-1978
        Mann, J.R. 1977
        Plaut, Helene 1976-1977
      - Correspondence - Plaut, [Feist] Frederick - Descendants, 1977-1986 (Box 2, Folder 66)
        Plaut, Michael 1984